你们都是镜片吧？
Lenses y'all, right?
让我们把那些人带进来。
Let's bring those in.
所以带上镜头道具，然后
So bring in a lens prop, And
超过n，让我们也被移除销毁，因为我喜欢，
over of n, let's also get removed for destroy because I like,
我不必做这些奇怪的拼接之类的。
I don't have to do these weird splices and whatnot.
我们会来的，我们会从 lamda 那里得到那个，所以
We'll come we'll get that from lamda, so
现在在创建我们可以说，事实追加数组。
now on create we can say, fact append array.
所以我们可以做over state，我们需要为习惯做一个镜头道具。
So we can do over state and we need to make a lens prop for the habits.
这就是我们想要改变正确的 elda 习惯，开销习惯。
That's what we want to change right elda habits, overhead habits.
我们要对最后一个论点表示抱歉。
We want to sorry states the last argument.
我们要附加习惯。
We want to append the habit.
酷，忘记了一点。
Cool, forgot a little.
让我们继续制作我们的小镜头命名空间
And let's go ahead and make our little lens namespace and
我们可能只需要考虑到这一点。
we could probably just do this in mind.
然而习惯和那将是lensProp，习惯。
Yet habits and that will be lensProp, Habit.
很酷，关于这个自动完成的小东西的一件事，
Cool, one thing about this little autocomplete thing,
它告诉我我实际上是正确导入的，所以这很好。
it tells me I actually imported it right, so that's nice.
很酷，所以我们都看到了它是如何工作的。
Cool, so we all see how that works.
让我们看看这是否通过 a, b 根本不起作用。
Let's see if that goes through a, b not working at all.
[笑]好吧，这里发生了什么？
[LAUGH] All right, what's happening here?
所以我们说的是习惯，附加习惯。
So we're saying over the habits, append the habit.
你认为这应该有效吗，所以
And do you believe that should work, so
有人看到任何问题吗？
anybody see any issues?
&gt;&gt; 养成习惯。
&gt;&gt; Structure the habit.
&gt;&gt; 在您自己的镜头道具中养成习惯。
&gt;&gt; Habits in your own lensprop.
&gt;&gt; 谢谢，就是这样。
&gt;&gt; Thank you that's it.
好 ib，c 真好。
Good i b, c it's so nice.
好吧，如果我破坏，让我们摆脱清除整个事情，
All right and if I destroy let's get rid of cleared the whole thing out,
我是故意这样做的。
I did that on purpose.
[笑]好吧。
[LAUGH] All right.
所以让我们用镜头做同样的事情，为什么不呢？
So let's do the same thing with lenses why not
过习惯删除 ID x 删除一个是删除
over habits remove the ID x remove one is remove
基本上就像拼接或状态流量。
is basically like splice or the state traffic.
然后运行这个 a、b 和 c 的实际属性，
And then were run this a, b and c the actual property,
很酷的字母 b，所以我们做得很好，我们很高兴。
cool letter b, so we're doing great, we're very happy.
我们正在使用 Montes，我们得到了所有的东西，但是
We're using Montes, we got all the stuffs but
令我烦恼的一件事是每次
one thing that kind annoying me is that each time
我们不得不说，我该怎么说？
we're having to kind of, how do I say this?
我们必须处理这种状态并进行管理，比如添加它。
We have to deal with this state and managing, like adding to it.
如果相反，我们真的回来了，
What if instead, we actually returned,
我们刚刚返回了一个状态，它刚刚为我们合并了它。
we just returned a state and it just merged it for us.
我们不必处理合并这些东西，对吧？
We didn't have to deal with merging this stuff, right?
所以这个对象分配例如说我有一个状态和
So this object assign for instance is saying I have a state and
当我们添加新操作时，您是我们应用程序的开发者
it's on you as a developer of our app, as we add new actions
随着时间的推移，始终确保您将状态合并回。
over time to always make sure you merge the state back in.
如果你可以只返回 merge 并且它是一个幺半群会怎样。
What if you could just return merge and it's a monoid.
是的，风的幺半群，所以
Right, monoids for the wind, so
现在我不必担心实际对象分配我的状态。
now I don't have to worry about actually object assigning my state.
让我们在那里创建一个幺半群。
Let's make a monoid there.
我们在这里做同样的事情，只是在这里出现和出现。
We do the same thing here, just emerge and emerge here.
所以这将要做的只是合并，与镜头，不是那么大
And so what this is gonna do is just merge, with the lenses, not such a big
处理我们只是打开状态改变一些东西的地方
deal where we're just opening up the state changing something and
返回整个状态，因此合并不会在这里购买太多，但在这里，
returning a whole state back so the merge doesn't buy as much here, but down here,
它很像我们只是改变了一点状态。
it does a lot like we're just turning a little bit of state.
它将为我们将其合并回状态。
It will merge that back into the state for us.
随着我们建造的越来越多，我们不必总是担心
And as we build more, we don't have to worry about always
管理整个状态结构而不是破坏它。
managing this whole state structure and not breaking it.
我们可以只退还我们关心的那一小块
We could just return the little piece that we care about
每个人都有这个想法。
everybody on board with this idea.
好吧，让我们继续合并。
All right, let's go ahead and make a merge.
回到我们今天的第一件事幺半群。
Back to our very first thing of the day monoids.
我们只会说我会暴露 X 并且我们会说，
And we'll just say I will expose the X and we'll concat that by saying,
获得另一个合并。
get another merge.
我们总是保持关闭，对象分配，制作一个漂亮的副本，所以我们不会破坏任何东西。
We always stay closed, object assign, make a nice copy, so we don't break anything.
也许我们可以回去尝试检查并确保它的性能超级好
Maybe we can go back and try to check and make sure it's super performing and
摆脱这个，但目前，我们只是为了安全起见
get rid of this but at the moment, we're just gonna be on the safe side and
制作一个漂亮的小副本。
make a nice little copy.
我们会说其他 .x，所以我们正在合并我们的 x
And we'll say other .x, so we're merging our x
与另一个 x 含义加上一个合并一个 1，
with another x meaning plus a merge a 1,
concat 合并一个 2，
concat merge a 2,
我想我希望正确的人获胜，所以这是有道理的。
I think I want the right one to win, so that makes sense.
这个会覆盖这个，就像我们如何定义它，所以工作。
This one's gonna overwrite this one, just how we're defining it, so work.
看看会发生什么，也许我们会翻转它，但是我们走了，所以我们进行了合并。
See what happens, maybe we'll flip that, but there we go, so we get a merge.
现在我必须去更新我们的主应用程序循环，对吗？
Now I have to go update our main app loop now, right?
让我们继续吧，去掉这些让我丧命的花括号。
Let's go ahead and just get rid of these curly braces killing me.
[笑] 如果你看到我写花括号和函数然后返回，
[LAUGH] If you ever see me write curly braces and a function and return,
我精神状态不好。
I'm in a bad space mentally.
[笑] 所以，我们在这里，我们在这个事件循环中
[LAUGH] So, here we are, we're in this event loop and
正如我们现在所说的这些函数返回一个淹没，对。
as we call these functions now the returning a submerge, right.
所以我们要做的是得到我们想要开始的状态
So what we'll have to do is get the state we wanna start with emerge of state
将其与出现的任何返回值连接起来。
working concat that with whatever this returns which is emerge.
然后好吧，concats 这就是整件事，
And then okay that concats It there's the whole thing,
我们不会在这里通过合并。
and we're not gonna pass a merge here.
所以让我们把它从合并中弹出，
So let's just pop it out of the merge,
弄出来就行了，在我们做完操作之后把它从x的类型里弄出来。
just get it out, get it out of the type of the x after we do the operation.
大家看看效果如何？
Everybody see how that works?
我们要合并这两个状态，所以
We're gonna merge the two states, so
这将返回对每一个的合并，然后我们将其取出。
this returns a merge on each of these and then we take it out.
太好了，它仍在工作。
Great, it's still working.
那个怎么样？
How about that?
然后我们点击 B，它显示 B，万岁。
And we click B, and it's showing B, hooray.
我已经不喜欢的一件事是我必须到处调用合并，所以
One thing I don't like already is that I have to call merge everywhere, so
让我们考虑一下。
let's factor that out.
让我们把它放回我们的事件循环中，它将摆脱这些
Let's put that back down into our event loop will get it out of these
这些小函数现在只返回一点点状态
these little functions that are just returning little bits of state now and
他们都被合并了，不是很好。
they're all being merged, not super nice.
所以我们只是把它合并在这里，很酷。
So we'll just put this in a merge down here, cool.
它有点失控了。
It's getting a little bit out of control.
让我们继续[笑]，暂时这样做。
Let's go ahead [LAUGH] and do that or something for the time being.
好的，我们将在这里连接这两个，
All right, and we'll concat these two right here,
我们会得到 x，我们就这样。
and we'll get the x, there we go.
所以它有点难看，我不会撒谎，但没关系。
So it's a little bit ugly, I'm not gonna lie, but that's fine.
从概念上讲并不难看，这是很多嵌套。
Not ugly conceptually, that's a lot of nesting.
但是在这里，当我们真正定义我们的函数时，看看它是多么干净。
But up here, when we're actually defining our functions, look how clean this is.
我不知道你是否曾经使用过氧化还原，但是
I don't know if you've ever used redox, but
到处都是 switch 语句，什么不是，好吗？
there's the littered with switch statements and what not, okay?
我们知道每次都会传入状态。
We know that state gets passed in each time.
我们知道我们可以翻转争论
And we know we can flip arguments around and
我们可以使用读者来解决这个问题。
we can use readers to kind of factor that out.
我注意到，我在这里没有使用状态，对吧？
And I noticed, I'm not using state down here, right?
我只是忽略它，那为什么我每次都必须传递它？
I'm just ignoring it, so why do I have to pass it in every time?
为什么我要处理它？
Why do I have to deal with it?
现在他们只是返回了一点状态。
Now they just returned a little bits of state.
我们只在想要绘制州地图时才要求它如何？
How do I how about we only ask for it when we want to map over the state and
然后我们会看看这个结果有多好。
then we'll do look how nice this worked out.
我可以抵消州的繁荣，繁荣。
I can cancel out the state's boom, boom.
所以它只是传入状态的第一类函数。
So it's just a first class function that passes in the state.
好吧，这很整洁，现在这只是一个需要习惯的函数。
All right, that's neat and now this is just a function that takes a habit.
嘿看，那个函数就像一个普通的函数。
Hey look, that function is like a normal function.
[笑] 不再是减速机了。
[LAUGH] It's not a reducer anymore.
所以让我们继续为这些事情做，让我们摆脱这里的状态，然后
So let's go ahead and do that for these let's get rid of the state here and
我们会在这里做完全相同的模式，我们会映射，我们会要求
we'll do the exact same pattern here, we'll map over, we'll ask for
国家，我们会拿回来的。
the state and we'll get it back.
然后在这里我们一起摆脱状态，我们甚至不必问
And then down here we get rid of the state all together, we don't even have to ask
对于它，我们很好，好吧，我们如何实现它，对吗？
for it, we're fine, okay, how do we how do we implement that, right?
好吧，我们必须马上被问到，所以
Well, we have to go get asked right off the bat, so
让我们从我们的 lib 类型中获取一个函数，
let's get a function from our lib types,
和功能已经问过所以只是从功能中询问。
and function has asked so just ask from function.
太好了，然后我们将在这里使用函数来为我们的东西建模。
Great, and then we'll use functions down here to model our stuff.
现在我可以把它包装在一个函数中，但是
Now I could wrap this in a function and all that, but
我要说这是一个返回 FN 类型的函数，对吗？
I'm gonna say this is a function that returns the FN type, right?
而这个我想我可以暂时把它放在那里
And this one I guess I could just put that right there just for now and
说，好吧，好吧，我有那个功能。
say, okay, well, I have a function of that.
我相信我们可以再次考虑这一点以回到那个状态，我还不确定。
I believe we can factor this out again to get back to that or not, I'm not sure yet.
我们会弄清楚的，那么，我们在哪里？
We'll figure it out, so, where are we?
现在不是将我们的函数称为状态，
Instead of calling our function a state now,
我们只是被有效载荷抓住了，对吧？
we're just caught with the payload, right?
但是然后我们用状态运行那个东西，它可以选择是否或
But then we run that thing with the state and it can choose whether or
不是它想使用它。
not it wants to use it.
好的，编译成功，看一下。
All right, compiled successfully, look at that.
走到这里，a，b 看看那多好。
Going over here, a, b look how nice that is.
我可以删除它，是的，我可以显示它，是的。
I could delete it, yep, I can show it, yep.
很酷，好吧，现在我们可以从任何地方提取状态。
Cool, all right, so now we're able to just pull state out of nowhere.
[笑] 而且，作为回报，我们在这里要做的是说，
[LAUGH] And, in return little bits we're gonna do here is say,
好吧，这个应用程序的结构可以不同，对吗？
all right again, the structure of this application can be different, right?
我们可以将其提取到我们的应用程序循环中。
We can pull this out into our app loop.
我们可以将所有这些东西拉到我们的控制器中。
We can pull all this stuff out into our controller.
我们可以把它移到一个图书馆等
We can move this into a library and so
我们不必在这里。
we don't have to here.
老实说，我不在乎我们是，你知道，
And honestly, I don't care that we are, you know,
达到了我想将它们移动到控制器和小模型中的地步
hit a point where I want to move those into a controller and a little model and
实用程序库和我的主要功能，即应用程序循环。
utility libraries and my little main function, which is the app loop.
但是你通常会看到很多这样的函数式程序，
But you typically see a lot of functional programs like this,
因为这无所谓。
because it just doesn't matter.
所以我认为它最终很重要，那就是你去做的时候。
And so I think it eventually matters and that's when you do it.